norwexcs.com 2016-12-03

# Norwex USA

**Last modified: MAY 2015**

Introduction  
Norwex USA, Inc. ("Norwex”, “we”, “us”, or “our") respects and is committed to protecting your privacy through our compliance with this policy.

This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to in it) describes the personal information that we collect from you, or that you provide on our websites [www.norwex.biz](https://www.norwex.biz/), [www.norwex.com](https://www.norwex.com/), and any other website on which we post a direct link to this policy (our "websites"), and how that information may be used or disclosed by us.

This policy does not apply to information collected on any third-party site or by any third-party application that may link to or be accessible from the websites.

Please read the following carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your personal information and how we treat it. By using or accessing our websites, you agree to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time and your continued use of the websites is deemed to be acceptance of such changes, so please check this policy periodically for updates.

[*Note: Our Safe Harbor certification is currently pending and not yet finalized.*] Norwex USA, Inc. complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries. Norwex USA, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Norwex USA, Inc.’s certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor/](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/).

## Children under the age of 13

Our websites are not intended for use by children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on the websites. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, please do not register on the websites, make any purchases through the websites or send any information about yourself to us. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:UScompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

## Information we collect about you

We collect several types of information from and about users of our websites, including: information you provide to us, information that we collect as you navigate through the websites (i.e., traffic and location data, IP addresses, and usage details through the use of certain technologies, including cookies and web beacons), as well as information we receive from third parties (e.g., our business partners), and which resources you access.

### Information you provide to us

We may collect and use the following information that you provide to us:

Information that you provide by filling in forms on our websites. This includes date and place of birth, financial account number (such as a checking account number), payment card number (such as credit card, debit card, etc.), social security number, job title, phone number, email address, address, last name, first name and any other information provided at the time of registering to use our websites, subscribing to our services, posting material or requesting further services or information;

Information that you provide when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by us;

Information that you provide when you report a problem with our websites;

Records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact us;

Your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them; and

Details of transactions you carry out through our websites and of the fulfillment of your orders.

### Uses made of the information

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information, in the following ways:

To present our websites and their contents in a suitable and effective manner for you and for your computer;

To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us;

To carry out our obligations, process and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;

To notify you about changes to our service;

To allow you to participate in interactive features of our services, when you choose to do so.

For marketing and promotional purposes so as to provide you with information about services we think you might like; and

To collect payments from you.

We may also use your information, or permit carefully selected third parties to use your information, to contact you about goods and services that may be of interest to you where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, or to provide your information to third parties for marketing purposes, please check the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data and / or adjust your user preferences accordingly in your account profile.

Depending on whether you have provided your consent we may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services that may be of interest to you and we, or they, may contact you about these by post or telephone.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (email or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those, which were the subject of a previous sale to you.

## Technology Usage

Like the vast majority of website providers, we collect details of your visit(s) to our websites. The information we collect concerns the resources that you access, and information about your computer and Internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration, marketing, and to report aggregate information to our advertisers.

### IP Addresses

Where, according to local law, IP addresses and the like are considered personal information, then we treat it as such.

### Web Beacons

Web beacons, also known as pixel tags, are electronic images contained on a website that permit us to count users who have visited our websites and to accumulate other statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain websites content and verifying system and server integrity). Web beacons are not used to access your personal information and are only used to compile aggregated statistics concerning use of the websites.

### Third-Party Advertisers

Some advertisements on the websites are served by third-party advertising companies. Please note that our advertisers may also use cookies and/or web beacons to collect aggregate and non-identifying information about our users. We do not have control over third-party advertisers' technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement, you should contact the responsible advertiser directly.

## User Contributions

You are responsible for any content, including personal information, that you contribute to be posted, published or displayed on the websites, or transmit to other users of the websites (collectively, "User Contributions"). Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to other users of the websites at your own risk. Although we limit access to certain pages, and you may set certain privacy settings for such information by logging into your account profile, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the websites with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions; therefore, we cannot guarantee who will view your User Contributions. We are not responsible for circumvention by third parties of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the websites. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of your User Contributions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or may have been copied or stored by other websites users. Proper access and use of information provided on the websites, including User Contributions, is governed by this privacy policy and our terms of use. Known or suspected violations should be reported to [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

## Disclosure of your information

We may disclose personal information that you provide via this websites to the following third parties:

To our group companies (i.e., our holding company and its subsidiaries and affiliates); and

Direct contractors and service providers we use to support our business, such as web hosting providers, web analytics providers, email service providers, and cloud-survey platform providers.

In the event (whether prospective or actual) of a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of Norwex’s assets, in which case personal information held by Norwex’s about its customers will be among the assets transferred to the (prospective) buyer.

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties to: 

Comply with any court order or other legal obligation; and

Enforce or apply our terms of use or terms of sale and other agreements.

Protect the rights, property, or safety of Norwex, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

## Your choices about how we use and disclose your information

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:

### Cookies

Cookiesare small files stored on the browser or the hard drive of your computer. The use of cookies helps us to improve our websites and to deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to: estimate our audience size and usage patterns, store information about your preferences so that we may customize our websites according to your individual interests, speed up your searches and recognize you when you return to our websites. 

Our websites uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our websites. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our websites and also allows us to improve our websites. You may set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, please note that some parts of our websites may then be inaccessible or not function properly.   
**If you register with us or if you continue to use our websites, you agree to our use of cookies.**

### Promotional Offers from Norwex

If you do not wish to have your email address used for promotional purposes by Norwex, you can opt out by checking the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data. You can also always opt out of receiving email information from us, other than the email informing you of the completion of user registration, correction of user data, or change of password, by logging into the websites and adjusting your user preferences in your account profile by checking or unchecking the relevant boxes or by sending us an email stating your request to [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:UScompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy). If we have sent you a promotional email, you may send us a return email asking to be omitted from future email distributions. This opt out does not apply to information provided to Norwex as a result of a product downloads or purchase, warranty registration, product service experience or other transactions.

### Personalized Advertising

If you do not want us to use your personal information that we gather to allow third parties to personalize advertisements we display to you, you can opt out by checking the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data. You can also always adjust your user advertising preferences accordingly in your account profile by checking or unchecking the relevant boxes or by sending us an email stating your request to [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:UScompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

### Unsubscribing

In each and every email that we send to you, there is an ‘unsubscribe’ hyperlink, which you may you use if you wish to ‘opt out’ of and stop receiving email communications from us. The hyperlink will direct you to our websites, where upon entering the email address that you no longer wish to receive Norwex emails, one last confirmation email shall then be sent to the email address you designate. Merely confirm that you do indeed wish to stop Norwex email’s being sent to you and that email address shall automatically be unsubscribed.

Alternatively, you may email Norwex at  [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:UScompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) with your request, stating ‘Unsubscribe’ in the header and what email addresses you wish not to receive Norwex emails and within ten business days, we shall ensure that such email addresses are unsubscribed and shall no longer receive any communications from us.

## Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:UScompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

Our websites may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### Your California privacy rights

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our websites that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:UScompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

### Access to information

You can access, change, update or delete personal information you have provided and your subscriptions or preferences regarding information you receive from us by contacting us using the information found in the Contact information section of this privacy policy or by logging into the websites and visiting your account profile page and making changes. We will implement your requested changes as soon as we reasonably can. When you edit your information or change your preferences, information that you remove may remain in our databases or backup media because it is not always possible to completely remove or delete information from those locations. Your access may be limited if the request is extremely impractical, would cause Norwex to take any action that would violate applicable law, or where the rights or privacy of others would be jeopardized or violated.

## Where we store your personal data

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password that enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask that you not share your password with anyone.

## Data security

We have implemented measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers behind firewalls. All payment transactions you make via our websites are encrypted using SSL technology.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the websites like message boards. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the websites.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our websites; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

## Changes to our privacy policy

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. It is your responsibility to visit this page from time to time to check for any change. Your continued use of the websites or our services shall be deemed to be your consent to such changes.

The date this privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. 

## Contact information

You may contact us with any questions you may have on our privacy policy. Please contact us by email at  [CDNcompliance@norwex.com](mailto:CDNcompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or [UScompliance@norwex.com](mailto:UScompliance@norwex.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or by regular mail at:

**If you are resident in USA:**  
Chief Information Officer  
Norwex USA, Inc.  
800 W. Bethel Road  
Coppell, TX 75019  
USA

**If you are resident in Canada:**  
Chief Information Officer  
Norwex Canada Inc.  
P.O. Box 714  
Stn Main   
Dauphin, Manitoba R7N 3B3  
Canada

**If you are a resident of the European Economic Area:**  
Chief Information Officer  
Norwex USA, Inc.  
800 W. Bethel Road  
Coppell, TX 75019  
USA

## Dispute Resolution for U.S. - EU Safe Harbor Claims

If a complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through Norwex USA, Inc.’s internal process, Norwex USA, Inc. has agreed to cooperate with the EU Data Protection authorities and to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the EU Data Protection authorities.

Thank you for taking the time to read our privacy policy
